漫威《神盾局特工》前情回顾
Previously on "Marvel's Agents Of S.H.I.E.L.D."...
你为什么想重建传送门  珍玛
Why do you want to rebuild the portal, Jemma?
因为我必须回去
Because I have to get back there.
我做过几十次模拟了
I've run dozens of simulations.
但巨石只是一种选择
The monolith was just one option, though.
我们不会放弃的  好吗
We're not gonna give up, okay?
那是什么  冻结胶质吗
What is it? Some kind of suspension gel?
可以让他们处于静止态  健康鲜活  但沉睡着
It keeps them in stasis... alive, healthy, just asleep.
斯特拉克
Strucker.
沃德在哪
Where do I find Ward?
我想完成沃德吩咐的任务
I tried to do what Ward wanted.
我想杀了他
I tried to kill him.
加纳教授吗
Professor Garner.
毛伊岛威雷亚海滩6个月前
你刚刚为了捕捉一个美好的瞬间反而毁了气氛
Did you just spoil a perfect moment by capturing it?
你在这个阳光下太美了
You looked too good, sun hitting you like that.
明天这时候我们就到家了
Well, this time tomorrow, we'll be home.
现在是谁在破坏气氛了
Look who's spoiling the moment now.
我要是不回神盾局你觉得怎么样
What would you say if I didn't go back to S.H.I.E.L.D.?
你是认真的吗
You're serious.
至少不马上回去
At least, not right away.
你这么说是因为身在海岛吗  还是
So, is this the island talking, or are you... I mean...
有很多原因会导致我们走不下去
There are a lot of reasons why this won't work...
无法维系
why we won't work.
有时我会忘记你多么直接
Sometimes I forgot how direct you are.
我不想成为原因之一
I don't want to be one of those reasons.
你不会的
And you won't be.
听着  我们成长了  也更加明智了
Listen, we're older now and wiser.
我不想第二次失去你
And I don't plan on losing you a second time.
怎么样
So what do you say?
想稳定下来吗
You want to go steady?
我们刚才是在讨论我们变老了吗
Weren't we just talking about how we're older?
是啊
Yes.
那好吧
All right, then.
敬新开始
To new beginnings.
我不知道梅琳达什么时候能回去  菲尔
I don't know when Melinda's coming back, Phil.
我们几天前才回到家
We only got home a couple of days ago.
我想谢谢你把嘉颖来世的东西送来
Wanted to thank you for sending over Jiaying's things from afterlife.
希望这些东西能对现在的异人族状况有所帮助
Hopefully, it'll help shed some light on our new Inhuman situation.
如果有什么发现我会告诉你的
I'll keep you posted if I find anything interesting.
还有  菲尔  别等梅琳达打给你了
And, Phil, I wouldn't wait for Melinda to call you.
好建议  谢谢
Good advice. Thanks.
好了
All right.
天哪
Oh, god.
我们不是怪物
We're not monsters.
你不能因为不知道该怎么做
You can't just lock us up in some ice prison
就把我们关在冰冻监狱里
because you don't know what else to do.
那不是什么监狱
No one's talking prison.
理论上来讲  那是个凝胶块
And, technically, it's a gel matrix.
他们把人置于静止态
They're putting people in stasis.
你可以把那理解为药物诱导性昏迷
Think of it as a medically induced coma,
在我们找到更好的解决办法前按下暂停键
a way to hit the pause button until we find a better solution.
更好的解决办法  那是什么意思
"A better solution." What does that mean?
ATCU正在寻找治愈方法
The ATCU's looking for a cure.
我并不是说所有人都得用
I'm not suggesting that's for everyone,
因为不是的  但也许有人会想...
because it's not, but some people might want to...
我们又不是病
We are not a disease.
我没那个意思
I didn't say that you were.
你不能指望人们
You can't just expect people
经历那样的巨变
to go through that kind of change
然后马上就能控制好
and immediately have a handle on it.
你还记得我当初有多害怕吗
Do you remember how scared I was at first?
记得  我还记得你冲自己开了冰冻枪
Yes. I also remember you iced yourself
以防伤害到我们
so that you wouldn't hurt any of us.
-你得承认事情有点失控了  -我知道
- You've got to admit, things are getting out of hand. - I know.
有人在不受控的环境中发生转化
People are changing in uncontrolled environments...
我知道  但人人都该有个做自己的机会
I know, but everyone deserves a chance to be who they are.
这你就错了
That's where you're wrong.
你是被你自己的经历误导了
You're being seduced by your own experience.
你学会了如何控制自己的异能
Just because you learned how to control your powers
不代表其他人也都能学会
doesn't mean everyone else will.
万一有人在伤害自己
I mean, what if a person's hurting themselves
或他们身边的人呢
or those around them?
要是他们无法自制怎么办
What... what if they can't stop?
就拿鞭笞来说吧
Take Lash.
要是朝那怪物头上打一枪还不能阻止他
If putting a bullet in that monster's head doesn't do the trick,
那怎么办
then what?
这可不公平  他只是个例
That's not fair. That's one guy.
大部分异人的转化会介于我和他之间
Most inhumans fall somewhere between me and him.
我今天要见总统和他的顾问们
And that's the message I'm hoping the president
希望到时候他们能听进去这话
and his advisors will hear when I meet with them today.
你要见美国总统
The president of the United States?
是个密会
It's off the books,
但国际社会要齐聚一堂
but the global community's coming together
讨论这些能力增强者的未来
to discuss the future of enhanced people.
会面地点在科罗拉多州的北美防空联合司令部
We're meeting at NORAD in colorado.
但神盾局对外是不存在的
But S.H.I.E.L.D. isn't supposed to exist.
所以我的身份会是ATCU的顾问
That's why I'm going in as a consultant for the ATCU.
-所以是罗莎琳・普莱斯  -安排的  对
- So Rosalind Price... - Arranged it, yes.
我们坐和风一号过去  路上接她
We're taking Zephyr One, picking her up on the way.
你确定这是个好主意吗
Are you sure this is a good idea?
我们不能失去这样的机会
We can't afford to miss it.
所以我希望你能在会面前跟罗莎琳谈谈
That's why I want you to talk to Rosalind before the meeting.
让她站在你这边
Win her over to your side of things.
可能是让神盾局重见天日的好开端
Could be a real start toward legitimizing S.H.I.E.L.D.
但如果你能拿出一个成功的异人案例
But it might help if you can present a successful
可能会有帮助
inhuman case,
一个在双方看来都不极端的案例
one that's not an extreme on either side.
乔伊・古铁雷斯该做重新评估了
Joey Gutierrez is due for reassessment.
我很愿意去看看他进展如何了
I'd be more than happy to check in on him, see how he's progressing.
总没坏处
Couldn't hurt.
我同意
I agree.
我会在你们降落前把报告发去
I can send you my report while you're in the air.
谢谢你的帮助
Thank you for your help on this.
我就是来帮忙的
It's what I'm here for.
不
No.
我是不明白你为什么给我打电话
I just don't know why you're calling me.
好吧  把位置发给我
All right. Give me your location.
我去找你
I'll meet you there.
加纳博士
Dr. Garner.
你好像要去实验室
Looks like you're heading to the lab.
这是个好迹象  对吗
That's a good sign, right?
我在努力
I'm trying.
我们都在努力
We're trying.
有时候我觉得  或许不该把一切
Sometimes it just feels like it would've been best
都告诉菲兹
if I hadn't told Fitz everything.
你说出真相是对的  珍玛
You did the right thing in telling the truth, Jemma.
秘密会从内心吞噬你
Secrets can eat you up from the inside.
你在忙吗
You busy?
不  不
Uh, no. No.
抱歉  我最近都不怎么常来
Sorry I haven't been in here more.
你不必解释的
There's... there's no need to explain.
那是什么
What's that?
是我的手机
It's my phone.
我当时正好带着
I had it with me.
我拍了照片  录了音
Uh, I took pictures, made some recordings
来记录我在那里的生活
to document my time there.
损毁很严重  但我还是留着作为纪念
It's quite damaged, but I kept it on me as a remembrance.
我希望你能
I was hoping you could...
恢复数据
Recover the data.
也许没什么用
It's probably pointless.
不  也许有用
Yeah, no. Maybe not.
我觉得你该自己...
Just thought if you saw it for...
看看  嗯
Myself, yeah.
总是很高兴有你做我的第二双眼睛
I always felt better having you as my second pair of eyes.
试试又无妨  我这就开始
Well, couldn't hurt to try. I'll get right on it.
谢谢  菲兹
Thank you, Fitz.
但我不知道他会变身
But I didn't know he'd change into that thing.
你在担心安德鲁吗
You worried about Andrew?
还是郁闷那个斯特拉克小子还没来得及交代
Or pissed that the Strucker kid went comatose
就陷入昏迷了
before he could talk?
总部的人都说安德鲁没事
Well...everyone at HQ says that Andrew's fine.
至于九头蛇...
And as far as Hydra...
我们会抓到他们的
we'll get them.
我希望你能留下
I hope you stick around.
我们如今要对付的可不只是九头蛇
Hydra's not the only thing we're facing these days.
异人族状况  还有我们在找的那个怪物
Between the inhumans, this monster we're hunting,
ATCU又盯我们盯得紧紧的
And the ATCU on our ass,
我们需要一切帮手
We need all the help that we can get.
怪物
Monster?
是啊  那个喜欢杀死其他异人的大丑怪物
Yeah. Big ugly thing, likes to kill other inhumans.
你们一直在追踪他吗
You've been tracking him?
试图追踪
Trying.
他能变身成普通人类  简直没法找
Transforms into a man, which makes him impossible to find.
飞行记录
安德鲁・加纳  飞行日志
安德鲁・加纳
梅
May.
天啊  见到你真高兴
Oh, my God. It's good to see you.
我得走了
I-I got to go.
去哪
Go where?
我得和安德鲁谈谈
I, uh, need to talk to Andrew.
他在给一个新异人做心理评估
He's doing a psych eval on one of the new inhuman recruits.
我去隔离舱看过  他不在
I checked the containment room. He's not...
不  他去了基地外的一个训练场
No, he's at a training facility off-site.
在哪
Where?
神盾局训练场  代号  茧
我现在可以创造东西了
I can actually create things now.
你对此是什么感觉
And how does that make you feel?
挺高兴的
Excited, you know?
我现在控制力强多了
I have so much more control now.
加纳博士
Dr. Garner?
控制  是的
Control. Yes.
这很重要
That's important.
黛西觉得我能成为神盾局的资源
Daisy thinks I could be a real asset to S.H.I.E.L.D.
但她说我的命运掌控在你手里
But she said my fate is in your hands.
是的  乔伊
Yes, Joey.
确实是
It is.
你不用为我穿上衣服
Don't put your shirt on for my benefit.
听说了你跟九头蛇的泳池派对
Heard about your Hydra pool party.
我还担心你呢
And here I was worried about you.
我一直就不怎么喜欢开博
Never liked Kebo much myself.
名字太怪了
Funny name.
还把我关在后备箱里
Locked me in a trunk.
你没事吧
You all right?
-当然  -那就好
- Of course. - Good.
除掉沃德的一些核心成员
'Cause taking out some of Ward's key players
-让我们离找到那混蛋更进一步了  -不行
- brings us one step closer to finding the bastard. - No.
科尔森忙着应付黛西  现在是最好的时机
Coulson's busy with Daisy, so now is as good a time as any.
亨特  这
Hunter, it's just...
这不是个好主意
it's not a good idea.
是因为安德鲁吗
Is this about Andrew?
我以为这事已经过去了
'Cause I thought we were past all that...
既然他没事了
Now that he's all right, I mean.
好吧  事态是有点失控
Okay. Did things get slightly out of control? Yes.
但是显然我都能处理好
But nothing I couldn't handle, obviously.
而且我做的一切都是为了保护你
And everything I did was to protect you.
芭比  你能停一会儿吗
Bob, will you stop for one second?
我觉得我们俩都不该去抓沃德
I don't want either of us to go after Ward.
你在开玩笑  对吧
You... you're joking, right?
你什么时候决定的
Since when?
不管是什么  直说吧
Whatever it is, lay it on me.
我觉得你最近鲁莽又愚蠢
I think you've been reckless and stupid.
我能收回我刚刚说的话吗
Can I take back what I just said?
为了什么
And for what?
这样沃德就再不能伤害你了
So Ward won't lay a bloody finger on you again!
这就是为什么
That's what.
对  我很蠢  因为我爱你
Yeah, I'm stupid, because I love you!
我不需要一个拯救我的英勇骑士  亨特
I don't need a knight in shining armor, Hunter.
我需要你活着
I need you alive.
我不想失去你
I don't want to lose you.
好吧  你说得对
Okay. You're right.
也不想我们俩都迷失其中
Or lose ourselves.
因为太执着于复仇
Become so obsessed with revenge
自己也变成他那样的魔鬼
that we... we turn into monsters just like him.
我还从没登上过空中基地呢
Never walked onto a flying base before.
看来可以把这个从我的遗愿清单里划掉了
Guess I can cross that off my bucket list.
那么  从哪里开始参观
So, where does the tour begin?
这要看黛西了  她带你参观
That's actually up to Daisy. She's gonna show you around.
生日快乐  珍玛
Happy birthday, Jemma!
Happy birthday, Jemma.
没有你在不一样
It's not the same without you here.
替我跟你父母问好  我们回头见
Say hi to your parents for me, and I'll see you soon.
两个卫星  我的天哪
Two moons. Bloody hell.
菲兹
Fitz...
我有可能在其中一个极地  但是很奇怪
It's possible I'm on one of the poles, but it's strange.
星星和两个卫星
The stars and the two moons,
不断地消失  又再出现
they keep disappearing and reappearing.
但没有太阳
But there's no sun.
就是没有太阳
There's never a sun.
上次你见到我时  我一团糟
Last time you saw me, I was a wreck.
现在我觉得很有力量
Now I feel... empowered.
听起来可能很蠢
That probably sounds stupid.
听起来你开始接受这是你的一部分
Sounds like you've grown to accept that this is a part of you.
说实话  作为建筑工人
Honestly, as a construction guy,
通常要花几个月建好的工程
the idea that I could build in a day
我一天之内就能搞定
something that would normally take months...
这简直不真实
it's unreal.
或是拆毁什么
Or tear something down.
如果有必要的话
Yeah. If I have to.
就这么轻松
Just like that.
黛西想要组建一支队伍  是吗
Daisy's trying to put together a team of soldiers, right?
-进行对抗  -对抗邪恶
- To fight. - To fight evil.
我可以成为很好的武器
I could be a real weapon against it.
危险的武器
A dangerous weapon.
这就是我担心的事
That's what I'm worried about.
我们以为没人...
We weren't expecting anyone to...
梅琳达  怎么了
Melinda, what's going on?
把古铁雷斯先生带回基地
Take Mr. Gutierrez back to base.
-我们正在会诊  -加纳博士
- We're in the middle of a session. - Dr. Garner...
会诊结束  带他走
Not anymore. Do it now.
长官  我们有规定的
Ma'am, we have protocols.
那就按规矩走  然后带他离开
Take care of them, then go.
走吧
Come on.
这是怎么回事
What's all this about?
我们得谈谈
We need to talk...
单独谈谈
once we're alone.
谢谢你来
Thanks for coming.
不必紧张
You can settle down.
没人知道我们在这里
No one knows we're here.
你睡过觉吗
You getting any sleep?
一直被人追杀  很难有机会睡
It's kind of hard when I'm being hunted nonstop.
我其实只担心
I'm really only worried
那个想把我胸口炸穿的人
about the one who wants to blast a hole through my chest.
如果你有那人的情报  为什么不找黛西
If you've got intel on the guy, why not call Daisy?
因为我不能让她也陷入危险
'Cause I can't put her life at risk, too.
我去找了我的朋友
I went looking for my friends.
他们不是失踪了就是死了
And those who aren't missing are dead.
为什么跟我说这些
You're telling me this why?
因为你曾跟我一起对付那东西
Because you fought by my side against that thing.
所以你就排除了嫌疑
It eliminates you as a suspect.
我怎么可能有嫌疑
Why would I be a suspect?
因为你是神盾局的
Cause you're with S.H.I.E.L.D.
好吧  我...不太理解
Okay. I... I'm not sure I'm following.
鞭笞就在神盾局里
Lash is in S.H.I.E.L.D.
如果你肯帮我  我就能证明
And with your help, I can prove it.
谢谢你带我参观
I appreciate you showing me around like this.
我们建了这个隔离舱  帮助转化中的异人
We built this module to help those in transition.
这是由适应性材料建成的
It's made out of adaptive material,
能控制各种异能
so it can contain all sorts of powers.
而且防弹  当你这样的人要朝
It's also bulletproof, which comes in handy
我这样的人开枪时  就派上用场了
when people like you shoot at people like me.
你真觉得这更人道吗
And you really think this is more humane?
我们的目标是观察异人  教化他们
Our goal is to observe people, educate them,
确实  这需要时间  但是...
and, yes, it can take time, but...
我们并不总是有时间的
We don't always have that luxury.
但把异人丢在一边  当他们不存在
But throwing people away like they don't even exist
这样就好吗
is the answer?
-我们没有这样做  -看起来就是这样
- That's not what we're doing. - Sure as hell looks like it.
没那么简单
Well, it's not that simple.
你就承认吧
Just admit it.
你惧怕我这样的人  惧怕我们的能力
You're afraid of people like me, afraid of our power.
当然
Absolutely.
你了解自己的能力吗
Do you even know your own strength?
比方说  你能击落这架飞机吗
Could you take down this plane, for instance?
我不会那样做的
I wouldn't do that.
但如果你想呢
But if you wanted to?
你现在就能杀了我
You could kill me right now.
人类就已经够吓人了
Mankind's scary enough as it is.
哪个疯子有把枪  我们都得小心了
Some psycho gets a gun, and watch out.
但如今  有些人自己就是武器
But now people are their own weapon.
不是每个人都...
Not everyone is like...
"有些"就已经够多了
"Some" is enough. That's all it takes.
-你只看到了糟糕的一面  -不是那样的
- You only see the terrible things. - That's not true.
-我能保护大家  -无所谓
- I protect people. - It doesn't matter.
你怎么能这么说
How can you say that?
有一个黛西・约翰逊  就会有一个鞭笞
Because for every Daisy Johnson, there's a Lash,
你不这么想  就是愚蠢
and it's ignorant for you to think otherwise.
梅琳达  你倒是说句话
Melinda, talk to me.
究竟怎么回事
What's all this about?
我需要知道真相
I need to know... for myself...
在其他人卷进来之前
before anyone else gets involved.
你想知道什么
Know what?
我看了你的飞行日志  我追查了你的活动
I saw your flight logs. I tracked your movements.
至少五个异人被害时  你都在50公里范围内
You were within 30 miles of at least five inhuman deaths.
你为什么要去查我的飞行日志
Why are you looking at my flight logs?
我还查了你的医疗记录
Pulled your medical files, too.
你的血检报告被删除了
Your blood work was deleted.
可能是西蒙斯不小心...
So, maybe Simmons accidentally...
你以为你掩藏了行踪  但是并没有
You thought you covered your tracks, but you didn't.
梅琳达  你到底想说什么
Melinda, honestly, what are you getting at?
冯・斯特拉克那孩子还活着
That Von Strucker kid was alive.
他并没有死于爆炸
He didn't die in that blast.
我找到了他
I tracked him down.
他把你做的事都告诉我了
He told me what you did.
我做的事
What I did.
有个孩子说我...
So some kid says I...
他没有说谎
He wasn't lying.
他脸上的表情
The look on his face...
是纯粹的恐惧
it was pure terror.
你到底怎么了
What happened to you?
-你可以告诉我  -梅琳达
- You can tell me. - Melinda...
不要骗我
Don't lie to me.
你不会想知道的
You don't want to know.
-他说你是怪物  -梅琳达  不要
- He said you were a monster. - Melinda, don't...
怎么会这样
How could this even happen?
梅琳达  别问了
Melinda, stop!
安德鲁  拜托
Andrew, please!
-拜托  -闭嘴
- Please! - Stop!
三周过去了  菲兹
It's been three weeks, Fitz.
如果我不找点什么  如果我不吃东西
If I don't find something, if I don't eat,
是活不下去的
I won't make it.
菲兹  你好
Fitz, hi.
我不知道我为什么还在跟你说话
I don't know why I'm still talking with you...
还继续录我自己
why I'm recording myself.
你是永远不会看到了  是吗
You're never gonna see this, are you?
我还是没找到水
I still haven't found water,
而且...我...
and it's, um... well, I...
我...
It's, uh...
我很难集中注意力
I'm having trouble focusing,
我努力想保持乐观
and I'm trying to stay positive.
但是我害怕
But I'm scared.
我很害怕  菲兹
I'm scared, Fitz.
你还记得我们第一次见面吗
Do you remember when we first met?
我还记得
I do.
你少言寡语  脸色苍白
You were so quiet and pasty, and...
那么聪明又帅气
so incredibly smart, handsome...
这感觉很奇怪吧
Quite a strange feeling... isn't it?...
不想跟一个人分开
Never wanting to be without someone.
你一定很烦我总是跟着你
You must have been so annoyed, me following you around all the time.
没有
No.
从来没有
Never.
有时我会想我们的晚餐
I imagine our dinner sometimes...
去哪里  吃什么
Where we'd go, what we'd eat.
其实我经常想我们两人的事
I wonder about us a lot, actually.
在佩思郡有一间小农舍
There's this small cottage in Perthshire
我小时候  和家人度假
We drove by once when I was a girl,
曾开车经过那里
some... some...family holiday,
不知为什么
and I don't know why,
我觉得它很可爱
but I... I found it so lovely.
我现在还会想起它
I still think about it...
在那里我们可以一起...
A place where you and I could have...
但也就是想想吧
But that's that, I suppose.
不知道这块电池还能用多久
I'm not sure how long this battery will last.
我该省点电
I should save it, just in case,
以防有更重要的事要做
for more important things.
但如果可以  我还会对你自言自语
But I'll still talk to you on my own, if that's all right.
我会永远与你同在  菲兹
I'll always be with you, Fitz.
卡尔弗大学  老行政大楼
太好了  你醒了  对不起
Oh, thank god you're awake. I am so sorry.
我没想伤害你  我慌神了
I-I didn't want to hurt you. I... I panicked.
这是在哪
Where are we?
我们不能留在神盾局的机构里
We couldn't stay there, not with S.H.I.E.L.D.
我需要时间解释
I needed time to explain.
之前有多少次我差点就告诉你了
You don't know how many times I almost told you.
只是  我不知道怎么说
I just... I didn't know how.
我也不想这样的
I didn't ask for this.
天呐
Oh, god.
你都做了什么
What have you done?
梅琳达  别这样
Melinda, don't.
放  开  我
Let me go!
别这样  我不知道我会做出什么事来
Don't do that! I don't... I don't know what I'll do.
我会再次被本能控制的
Instinct will take over again...
就像在便利店里那样
Like it did at the convenience store.
本能
Instinct?
我没想伤害任何人
I didn't want to hurt anyone,
但我不知道是怎么回事
but I... I didn't know what was happening.
你杀了那么多人
You killed all those people.
怎么回事
How?
什么时候发生的
When did this... when did...
离开夏威夷后
After Hawaii.
黛西的妈妈有很多记录
Daisy's mom kept records.
我当时在浏览  做研究  了解情况
I was going through them for any insight, for research.
我找到一本书
And I found a book.
上面有很多异人的名字
It had all these names of inhumans.
嘉颖一定是布下了泰瑞根水晶
Now, Jiaying must have rigged it with a terrigen crystal
以防不能穿过迷雾的人翻看
to keep out anyone who couldn't survive the mist.
算我走运
Lucky me.
起初  我如释重负  我活下来了
At first, I was relieved. I survived.
但我知道有些不对劲
But I knew something had happened.
我觉得恶心
I felt sick and nauseous.
有一种强烈的脉动感
There was this intense pulsing,
好像我的心在脑子里跳动
like my heart was in my head.
我觉得我变了
I felt different, like...
就像我的一部分被释放了
like a part of me was unlocked.
释放
Unlocked?
我不知道还能怎么说
I don't know how else to... I just... I had to...
我就像受了驱使  必须接近他们
It was as if I was compelled. I had to be near them.
那些异人
The inhumans.
我不知道为什么  那感觉很强烈
I didn't know why. It was... it was intense.
我有了一种新的欲望  我有种
I had this new desire. I had a...
我皮肤上有种饥渴
had a hunger...on my skin.
直到我真遇到了一个  我的身体不由自主
It wasn't until I finally met one that my body took over,
发起了攻击
and I... I lashed out.
然后我有种释然感
And then I felt relief.
但是有你在
But with you...
安德鲁
Andrew?
你在里面吗
You in there?
你不会理解的  我必须远离你
You wouldn't understand. I had to keep you away.
-所以你才...  -对  我是个懦夫
- That's why you... - Yeah, I was a coward.
我想告诉你的  但我担心
I wanted to tell you, but I was worried that...
你必须明白
you had... you had to know.
我离开你不是因为不爱你
I didn't end things with you because I don't love you.
我是为了保护你
I did it to protect you.
我还爱着你  梅琳达
I'm still in love with you, Melinda.
我需要你帮助
And I need your help.
让安保人员离开后他们去了哪里
And where did they go after may dismissed the security detail?
有消息就通知我
Update me as you know more.
一切都好吧
Everything all right?
还不清楚
Not sure yet.
或许只是办公室恋情出了岔子那么简单
Could be as simple as a workplace romance gone wrong.
听上去并不简单啊
That doesn't sound simple.
你刚刚不是正在跟我说
I think you were in the middle of telling me
你和黛西现在多亲了吗
what great friends you and Daisy are now.
我可能有点过分了
I may have overstepped.
但有件事可以确定  那姑娘挺有血性
But one thing's for certain... that girl's got fire.
你还没跟别人提过她吧
And you still haven told anyone about her.
我是遵守承诺的人  菲尔
I keep my promises, Phil.
他们不知道
They have no idea.
新打扮啊
New look?
其实一直这么打扮
Old look, actually.
但好久没系了
It's been a while, though.
我来吧
Uh, may I?
好啊
Sure.
那么
So...
你打算告诉我究竟怎么回事吗
you gonna tell me what really happened?
我可不太相信什么被鲨鱼袭击的说法呢
'cause I'm not quite buying the shark-attack bit.
你不信啊
You're not buying that?
我一个手下给砍掉的
One of my men cut it off.
救了我一命
Saved my life.
砍你的手救命吗
By chopping off your hand?
你得在场才会理解
You kind of had to be there.
疼吗
Does it hurt?
每天都疼
Every day.
幻肢疼
Phantom pain.
你失去的东西却让你感触最深
Thing that's missing is the thing that you feel the most.
让人难以忘记
Makes it hard to forget.
那就别忘记
So maybe you don't.
但向前看也很重要
But it's also important to look ahead,
看到未来
see what's in front of you.
要到北美防空联合司令部了吗
We close to NORAD?
不是  又有一架昆式战斗机请求降落
No. Another quinjet's requested to dock.
林肯  你怎么来了
Lincoln, what are you doing here?
你在哪找到他的
Where'd you find him?
是他来找我的  他有关于鞭笞的情报
He came to me. He's got intel on Lash.
她是ATCU的吗
She ATCU?
我们现在在合作
We're working together now.
是的  我们都想抓住那东西
Yeah, we all want to catch that thing.
坎贝尔先生  你都到这儿了
Well, Mr. Campbell, you've come this far.
说说吧
What do you have to say?
我们这些从来世出来的人  都会融入环境
Those of us from Afterlife, we were trained to blend in.
来世
Afterlife?
回头跟你讲
I'll explain later.
但那东西却老能找到我们
And yet that thing keeps finding us,
杀了我很多朋友
killed most of my friends.
林肯告诉我一些名字
Lincoln gave me names.
我跟我们能辨认的尸体进行了核对
I checked them against the bodies we could identify.
所以我知道鞭笞是在用嘉颖的记录本找我们
That's how I knew Lash was using Jiaying's ledger to find us.
她的记录本
Her ledger?
她有一本异人族的族谱
She kept a genealogy of inhumans.
只有她可以使用  直到...
She was the only one allowed to use it, until...
直到被神盾局没收
Until S.H.I.E.L.D. recovered it.
据我所知只有一个人能看到这本族谱
And there's only one person I know who had access.
加纳博士
Dr. Garner?
但这不可能啊
But there's no way. It's not possible.
我也不愿相信
I didn't want to believe it, either.
你不止是说安德鲁有记录本
So you're not just saying Andrew has the ledger.
你是说
You're saying...
我今早看到梅查看他的飞行记录
I saw May access his flight logs this morning.
我跟她说过话
I talked with her.
她有些气急败坏  但我以为她是...
She was upset, but I thought that she...
她和安德鲁不见了  我刚得到消息
She and Andrew are missing. I just got word.
天呐
Oh, god.
改变飞行路线  去纽约
Reroute the plane... New York.
调出茧的卫星录像
Pull all the satellite footage from the Cocoon.
-我们得找到他们  -是  长官
- We need to find them. - Yes, sir.
我真不敢相信我会说这话
I can't believe I'm saying this,
但总统只能稍后再说了
but the president's gonna have to wait.
都听你的  我去知会他们
Whatever you need, I'll let them know.
安德鲁不会伤害她的
Andrew wouldn't hurt her.
他都杀了我们那么多人了
He's killed dozens of us.
或许他变身后就不知道自己在做什么了呢
Yeah, well, what if he doesn't know what he's doing once he turns...
昏迷过去了什么的
He... he blacks out or something?
异人不能变形的  不是那样的
Inhumans can't change form. That's not how it works.
我亲眼看到他的
I saw it myself.
不  我是说  那只是一时的
No, what I'm saying is, it's temporary.
他不会一直在人类和怪物之间转变
He won't always be able to shift between monster and man.
他还处于转化中
He's still in transition.
在渐渐变成异人
Becoming inhuman.
等转化完全结束后呢
And when that transition's complete?
他会永远成为鞭笞
He'll stay Lash, permanently.
你以为自己了解的那个人在渐渐消失
The man you think you know is disappearing,
或许他已经不在了
if he's not already gone.
安德鲁
Andrew...
如果不是我出现了
If I hadn't shown up...
你打算伤害乔伊吗
were you going to hurt Joey?
当然不会
Of course not.
你也知道我绝不会伤害黛西的
And you know I'd never lay a finger on Daisy.
但你却想伤害林肯
But you went after Lincoln.
那小子有阴暗面
That kid has a dark side.
你比别人都更能理解
You understand more than anyone.
想想巴林岛的事吧
Look at what happened in Bahrain.
什么
What?
你亲眼见识过异人族的本事
You saw firsthand what inhumans were capable of.
如果不是你杀了那个小姑娘
If you hadn't killed that little girl,
你周围的所有人都会遭殃
everyone around you would've suffered.
他们都会死  是你救了他们
They all would've died. But you saved them.
这不是你
This isn't you.
你绝不会说这种话
You would never say that.
不  梅琳达  我完全明白自己在说什么
No, Melinda, I know exactly what I'm saying.
你和我  我们是一样的
You and me... we're the same.
所以我需要你帮忙
That's why I need your help.
我根本没想伤害那个女孩
I never wanted to hurt that girl.
我知道
I know.
我知道  相信我
I know, and believe me,
我也不想做我做的这些事
I don't want to do what I'm doing, either.
但我必须做
I have to.
我知道你觉得我是迷失了
I know you think I've lost myself.
我没有
I haven't.
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do.
我知道
I know.
还记得我们第一间公寓吗
Do you remember our first apartment?
克兰布鲁克那间
The one on Cranbrook.
一卧  破蒲团当床
One room, a stupid futon for a bed,
还有那年冬天  冷得不像话
and that winter when it got so cold, we...
我们用炉子当暖气
We used the oven as our heater.
虽然不是取暖最保险的办法
And not the safest way to keep warm, but...
但很好使
it did the trick.
梅琳达
Melinda...
这世界变得更复杂了  是吧
The world has gotten more complicated, hasn't it?
我知道我们不能假装一切不存在
I know we can't pretend it all away.
但我还是你爱上的那个男人
But I'm still the same man you fell in love with.
我从未放弃你
I never gave up on you.
求你别放弃我
Please don't give up on me.
抱歉打搅了
Sorry to interrupt.
还在等乔伊的重新评估报告呢
Still waiting on Joey's reassessment.
菲尔
Phil...
你不明白
You don't understand.
我开始明白了
I'm starting to.
你没事吧
You all right?
我们是老朋友了
We're old friends.
所以我希望大家都能安安全全地离开
That's why I'd prefer to see everyone walk out of here unharmed.
但如果你有别的想法  我可不是一个人来的
But in case you got something else in mind, I'm not alone.
隔离舱安全
Containment module's secure.
收到
Copy that.
大堂小队正在就位
Hall team's getting into position.
记住  这是科尔森的行动
Remember, this is Coulson's op.
我们听他下令行动
We do not move unless he gives the order.
去吧
Go
他是不会束手就擒的
He's not gonna come quietly.
这事不非得悲剧收场
This doesn't have to go down badly.
我会确保你得到照顾
I'll make sure you're taken care of.
我理解你的难处  真的
I understand the position you're in... I do.
我并不羡慕你
And I don't envy it.
但我是在帮你
But I am trying to help you.
我们在面对一场爆发
We've got an outbreak on our hands.
他什么意思
What the hell does he mean by that?
冷静
Calm down.
科尔森有数
Coulson knows what he's doing.
你确定吗
You sure about that?
我只是想把良莠区分开
I'm simply trying to sort the good from the bad.
这是你给我的工作
You gave me this job.
这对治疗师的理解偏差太大了
That's a pretty poor interpretation of a therapist.
看看你周围
Look around you.
我们身处一座废弃大楼  梅被铐着
We're in some abandoned building, May's tied up...
你根本就有事
You're not okay.
我知道看上去什么样  但我有道德责任
I know how it looks, but I have a moral responsibility.
你很快就会明白
You'll see, soon.
我是在帮你忙
I'm doing you a favor.
他疯了
He's insane.
不是的  他只是病了
That's not true. He's just sick.
那野兽会冒出来的  你控制不了
The beast's gonna come out, and you can't control it.
别因为自己跟他有仇  就恶化情况
Don't make things worse 'cause you got an axe to grind.
他不会乖乖让我们带走他的
He's not just gonna let us take him.
他会防卫自己的
He's gonna defend himself.
别跟他动手
Do not engage.
我们要听科尔森的命令
We move on Coulson's order.
我杀的都是该杀之人
I've only killed those who deserve it.
是谁让你做法官  陪审团和刽子手了
Who the hell made you judge, jury, and executioner?
你干什么
What are you doing?
你得赶紧把他带走
You've got to get him out of here, now!
林肯
Lincoln...
你撕碎了我的朋友  你没这个权利
You tore my friends apart. You have no right!
-够了  -冷静点  安德鲁  求你
- That's enough. - Calm down, Andrew, please.
我完全有权
I have every right.
安德鲁听我说  我们能帮你
Andrew, listen to me. We can help you.
ATCU就快找到治愈方法了
The ATCU is close to a cure.
我就是解决办法
I am the cure.
不
No!
趴下
Get down.
林肯和鞭笞在大楼东侧
Lincoln and Lash are in the east wing of the building.
得把他关进隔离舱里
We have to get him to the module.
是  长官
On it, sir.
菲尔
Phil...
我们的目标是抓住他  不是杀了他
Our goal is to capture, not kill.
我们得让林肯也同意
We just got to get Lincoln on the same page.
用这个
Try those.
真得把猎枪斧子赶紧做出来了
Really got to commit to that shotgun-axe idea.
我需要帮忙
Could use a little help here!
你位置在哪
What's your twenty?
安德鲁  我们是朋友
Andrew...we're friends.
或许只是熟人而已
Or maybe just acquaintances.
我们围住他了
We got him.
不要
No!
谢谢
Thank you.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
嗯
Yeah.
我不知道你还有这本事
I didn't know you could do that.
我也不知道
That makes two of us.
-他人呢  -我不知道
- Where is he? - No idea.
但我们得把他弄进隔离舱里
But we got to get him to the containment module...
得赶紧
Now.
我能把他引过去
I'll get him to where he needs to go.
安德鲁  住手
Andrew, stop!
闪开
Move.
来啊
Go on.
无所谓了
Might as well.
我想过我的死亡很多次
I've thought about my death enough times...
想过各种可能的死亡方式
the different ways that I could go.
但没想到会死在你手上
I just never thought it'd be you.
我一直不明白你为什么会娶我
I never knew why you married me.
我从来都不像你那么和气  善解人意
I was never as...kind and empathetic as you.
所以我会轻易离开
That's why it was so easy for me to walk away...
放弃了你
...why I gave up on you.
我离开你时  失去了一些东西
I lost something when I left you.
我不会再抛弃你一次了
I won't do it again!
但你必须停下来
But you have to stop this.
梅琳达
Melinda...
你怎么知道他不会死啊
How'd you know that wouldn't kill him?
我不知道
I didn't.
我就知道
I bloody knew it.
菲兹  没事吧
Fitz, you all right?
嗯  我觉得我...
Yeah, I think I've, uh...
记得这个吗
Remember this?
嗯  城堡密室里的
Yeah, from the castle chamber.
好的
Okay.
是那个小三吗
Oh, is that the other man?
我要把大家的想法说出来了
Well, I'm just gonna say what we're all thinking...
他长了张猪脸
he has a hog face.
说得太对了啊
He does have a hog face.
看看他所在的太空项目的标志
Okay. So, look at the logo of the space program he's with.
远星寻路者计划
如果把它倒过来  看上去就很相像了  是吧
And if you turn it upside down, they look similar, yeah?
-有点牵强啊  -可能吧
- Bit of a stretch, mate. - Possible.
好吧
Okay. Well, um...
如果在密室门上刻下了这个标识的组织
What if the group who carved this symbol into the chamber door
正是送威尔通过传送门的组织呢
is the same group that sent Will through the portal?
不是宇航局派威尔去的吗
I thought NASA sent Will through.
或许远远不止宇航局那么简单
Could go beyond NASA... way beyond.
别告诉我你觉得是有什么古老社团在幕后操纵
Please don't tell me you think some ancient order's behind all this,
即便是你  这也太疯狂了
'cause that's a bit mental even for you.
我知道听上去不靠谱
I know how it sounds, but
但这可是能通向别的星球的传送门啊
we're dealing with a portal that leads to another planet, so...
一切皆有可能
Anything's possible.
值得查查  菲兹
It's worth checking out, Fitz.
你打算接受科尔森的建议
You gonna take Coulson up on his offer,
多留一阵吗
stick around for a while?
不能一直逃啊
Can't run forever.
如果我们将人形的安德鲁置于静止态
If we put Andrew in stasis as a human,
就能减缓他的转化
it'll slow his transformation,
这样我们也有更多时间找到治愈办法
giving us more time to find a cure.
我不能假装理解你现在的心情
Now, I can't pretend to understand what you're going through,
但不管怎样
but for what it's worth...
如果我有机会拯救我爱的人  我一定会抓住
if I had the chance to save someone I love, I'd take it.
换了你会怎么办
What would you do?
这
Well...
这是个暂时的办法
it's a temporary solution.
这我们都承认
I think we can all acknowledge that.
但安德鲁帮过我
But Andrew helped me.
我愿用尽一切办法帮他
So I'd... I'd do whatever it takes.
我同意了
Do it.
你不跟上去吗
Do you need to go after her?
她不会想跟我谈的  现在不行
She wouldn't want me to, not right now.
今天好漫长
It's been a long day.
请你喝一杯啊
Buy you a drink?
太好了
Please.
你没事吧
You okay?
我睡不着
I couldn't sleep.
基地的窗户不多  我想
There aren't a lot of windows in the base, and I wanted to...
看日出
Watch the sunrise.
我
I, uh...
不能做保证
I can't make any promises,
但我可能有发现
but I think I may have found something.
或许能帮我们开启传送门
Might help us open up the portal.
真的吗
Really?
还有
And, um...
我修好了你的SIM卡
Fixed your sim card, so...
我听了你的录音  还看了录像
I heard your recordings and saw your video.
我还不知道你考虑过在佩思郡安家
Didn't know you thought about settling down in Perthshire.
那是在苏格兰
That's in Scotland.
我知道啦  菲兹
I know where it is, Fitz.
你说的那些话...
So when you said all those things about...
你当时很疲倦又脱水了
I mean, you were tired and deHydrated.
我当时头脑非常清醒
I was as clearheaded then as I've ever been...
我说那些话的时候
when I said all those things.
你觉得我们该怎么办
What do you think we should do about it?
现在
For now.
我们先看日出吧
Let's just watch the sunrise.
怎么了
What's wrong?
没什么
Nothing.
我没想到我有资格拥有这个
I never thought I deserved this.
什么  夏威夷之旅吗
What, a trip to Hawaii?
不是
No.
幸福
Happiness.
这样的幸福
This kind of happiness.
你当然有资格
Of course you do.
我们都有
We both do.
叫我来做什么
So, why am I here?
稍后再说
We'll get to that.
沃纳・冯・斯特拉克的事真是可惜
It's a shame about Werner Von Strucker.
为了你  希望他不会醒过来
I hope, for your sake, he doesn't wake up.
我并不担心
I'm not worried.
他很软弱  就像他父亲
He's weak, like his father.
小心哦  沃德先生
Ah, careful, Mr. Ward.
你为他费心费力
You paid a price for that boy.
你该问问自己这是否值得
You should ask yourself if it was worth it.
你把他的位置给了我
You gave me his location.
我是把你要的给了你
I gave you what you asked for.
但我不确定你提出的是对的要求
I'm just not sure that you're asking for the right things.
复仇只能给人一时的快感
Revenge only provides a temporary pleasure.
但也是快感
But a pleasure, nonetheless.
你该放开眼界  考虑大局
You should think on a grander scale.
会很大的
Oh, it'll be grand.
我砍掉神盾局的头怎么样
How about I cut off the head of S.H.I.E.L.D.?
没了菲尔・科尔森
Because without Phil Coulson...
神盾局就长不回来了
S.H.I.E.L.D. won't grow back.
失陪一下
Excuse me a moment.
普莱斯女士
Ms. Price.
我想为错过我们在北美防空联合司令部的见面道歉
I wanted to apologize for missing our meeting at NORAD.
我会尽快带他去见你
I will bring him to you soon enough.
时间就是金钱啊
Time is of the essence.
我得挂了  再联系
Oh, I better go. I'll be in touch.
你不用这么急着离开
You don't have to leave so soon.
先吃点早餐吧
How about some breakfast first?
-你做饭吗  -我从不做饭
- Are you cooking? - I don't cook.
但我是吃餐馆的专家
But I'm an expert at going out to eat.
这附近有好地方吗
Is there anything good around here?
鲁斯餐馆  就两个街区
Ruthie's diner is about two blocks away.
她家炒蛋很棒
She makes a mean scramble.
我应该还有时间
I think I can make time for that.
太好了
Good.